

# SOHEL AHMED **ANSARI**

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

+971564710320 sohel.ahmed.ansari@gmail.com Dubai

### **SKILLS**

React

Redux

Knockout.Js

**JQuery** 

Javascript (ES6)

HTML

CSS (Less)

Nodejs

Webpack

Git

TypeScript

Expert

Scrum

## HOBBIES

Video Games, Cooking, Travelling

## **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

M.H. SABOO SIDDIK COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING | MUMBAI 2009

# WEBSITES & SOCIAL LINKS

Website:

https://sohelansari.com

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sohelansari

Stackoverflow:

https://stackoverflow.com/users/22 79116/shinobi

## **ABOUT ME**

Experienced in everything from **converting designs into functional pages** to setting up **complex applications in modern frameworks**.

Specialized in handling front-end development and dealing with UI and UX of anything that I work on. I am always interested to put my views on the look and feel of the product.

History of working effectively in **agile** environments. Disciplined and hardworking **team player**.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### SENIOR PROGRAMMER

ONE.COM | DUBAI MAY 2016 - PRESENT

Working on front-end and backend development of Webshop (https://www.one.com/en/webshop)

Front-end is implemented using **Knockout.js**, backend is in Node.js and database in **PostgreSQL**.

We are now gradually re-writing this in **React** .

#### My role includes:

- Developing pixel perfect UI from given design and making it functional in React
- Fixing bugs in existing Knockout.js code.
- Converting Knockout.js code to React.
- Writing handlers in backend which is in Node.js and familiar with writing queries in PostgreSQL.
- Have worked on integrating payments through Credit card, iDEAL and Giropay using Stripe
- Acting as the communicator between my team of 5 developers with me in Dubai and the Project Manager in Copenhagen.
- Responsible for keeping an eye on the progress of the Sprint and making sure that the product manager is informed about any changes in it.
- Follow scrum methodology and Agile Software Development strategy.

Technologies include: React, Knockout.js, Javascript, HTML5, CSS, NodeJS, PostgreSQL

## SENIOR PROGRAMMER

NEXSALES CORPORATION | MUMBAI NOV 2014 - APR 2016

Worked on front-end development of a web app VoiceReach used by BPO for reaching out to prospects for marketing.

It was a single page web application written in AngularJS 1.3

## My role included:

- Getting involved in feature discussions and giving inputs on the UI/UX.
- Developing in AngularJS which includes creating HTML templates, styling CSS, writing code for angular controller, directive and services.
- Integrating external angular directives and using it.
- Follow scrum methodology and Agile Software Development strategy.

Technologies include: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, AngularJS 1.3, Bootstrap, NodeJS

## SOFTWARE ENGINEERING SR. ANALYST

ACCENTURE | MUMBAI FEB 2014 - NOV 2014

Worked on front-end development of a retail company client. Work included making templates for given psds and making it functional. Making sure the page is responsive on all devices.

Technologies include: HTML5, Javascript, jQuery, Sass, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Backbone.js

## SENIOR PROGRAMMER

Flash

ZEUS SYSTEMS PVT. LTD. | MUMBAI JUL 2009 - JAN 2014

Worked on many e-learning products to help kids of different age groups learn Maths and Science.

Technologies include: HTML5, Javascript, jQuery, Backbone.js, ActionScript 3,